Pouriya Zarbafian

Email: pouriya.zarbafian@gmail.com - Website: zarbafian.com

Background

Software engineer and programming expert with a broad experience in software and enterprise architecture; a team player with excellent analytical skills; results-oriented; the ability to work under pressure; dedicated to quality of work and efficiency.

Skills Summary

Design: Object Oriented Design, Enterprise Architecture, REST,

SOA, Data Modelling, XML

Backend developer: Spring, J2EE, Apache Camel, Rust, Python

Web developer: Angular 7, Javascript, Typescript, HTML5, CSS3

Databases: PostgreSQL, Oracle, MySQL, Neo4j, MongoDB

Mobile Development: iOs, Android, Xamarin

System Administration: Bash, SSH, systemd, Ansible

Tools: IntelliJ, Eclipse, Maven, Git, Nexus, Jenkins, FindBugs,

SonarQube, Logstash, Nagios

ECM: Capture, recognition, data extraction, data organization,

collaborative work, workflows and business processes

Other: Matlab, Machine Learning, Big Data, IoT (Raspberry and

Arduino), Raft

Research Student

Since March 2021: PhD Student at the University of Sydney

- PhD advised by Vincent Gramoli
- > Research in blockchain security, scalability, and the ordering of transactions
- Multiple publications in Rank A conferences

Work Experience

Aug. 2017 – Feb. 2021: Principal Software Engineer at Global Jet Luxembourg

- Design of the Enterprise Architecture (ESB, SOA, Camel, JMS)
- Mentoring of software engineers and external consultants
- Deployment of the new operational tool for flight planning in partnership with Boeing and Jeppesen: analysis and development lead of the various integrations between the enterprise service bus and the flight planning system (Java, Spring, ActiveMQ, XSD/XML, SOAP, REST, SQL)
- Maintenance of existing applications and development of new features (Java, Node.js, Angular, PHP, SQL, MongoDB)
- Setup of Enterprise Monitoring (Nagios, Logstash)
- ➤ Development of tools for software deployment and user administration (Bash, Ansible, SSH)

Jan. 2017 – April 2017: Senior Developer Freelance at Chambre des Députés

- Review and assessment of existing technologies and architecture
- Maintenance and development of new features

- Migration of existing web applications
- Uses Java EE, Swing, WebSphere

Oct. 2015 – Jan. 2017: Solutions Architect at q-leap S.A. for Luxaviation

- ➤ Led the integration of accounting systems into a business intelligence tool
- > Integration of various business applications via an ESB
- ➤ Migration of subsidiaries to a Salesforce based web-application
- > Development of several ETL jobs
- Used Talend DI and ESB

Jan. – Oct. 2015: Senior Consultant at Hamlet Consulting for SIX Payment Services

- Designed and developed bank interfaces for the Payment Card Industry
- ➤ Hands on experience with EMV and various ISO 8583 based banking protocols
- Created a centralized logging repository to ensure time saving searches
- ➤ Used JEE, Spring, Maven, REST, Swing, Hazelcast, and Lucene

2010 - 2014: Analyst-developer/Test engineer at IRIS Luxembourg S.A. (Canon Group)

- Designed and developed new features on IRISNext, IRIS' solution for document management (Java, Spring, Tomcat)
- ➤ Participated in the development of cloud solutions for OCR, web scan, and invoice processing (Applet, ImageIO, GWT)
- > Tested and insured quality with continuous integration and non-regression tests
- > Validated new functionalities on existing products and new products
- Led and created a multi-level training program for end users, project teams, and developers

2005 - 2009: Researcher at Luxembourg Institute of Science and Technology

- Migrated the IT environment of a government institution to service-oriented architecture
- > Applied research in Service Oriented Architecture and Model Driven Engineering
- Designed and developed data exchange, calculation, and payment
- Used EJB 3.0, JBoss, Oracle, PL/SQL, and SOAP

| Education | |
|-------------|--|
| 2020 | Deep Learning by deeplearning.ai on Coursera. Certificate earned on February 11, 2020 |
| 2016 | An Introduction to Programming the Internet of Things (IOT), a 6-course specialization by University of California, Irvine on Coursera. Specialization Certificate earned on March 8, 2016 |
| 2015 | Machine Learning by Stanford University on Coursera. Certificate earned on November 24, 2015 |
| 2002 – 2005 | Master's degree in Electrical and Computer Engineering from CentraleSupélec, France |
| 2000 – 2002 | Associate's degree in Sciences of Matter, Université Paul Sabatier Toulouse, France |

Languages

French First language

English Fluent Spanish Fluent Farsi Fluent